SARUMATHY B K

#50/39, Santhaveli 04th cross St Mylapore Chennai- 600 004 charu.k.karan@gmail.com

9952061245

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Total of about 6 years of experience as HR Executive, expertise in Recruitment, preparing job description, evaluation, organization structuring, training, employee engagement, performance management and development, reward & recognition, policy formulation and implementation, talent acquisition, retention and vendor management.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Randstad(Sutherland) - Team Lead -May 2022 - Till Date

Recruitment

- Responsible in taking care of the end-to-end volume hiring for the Consumer lending business (BFSI). Create effective JD & Post in Job Portal (Active: Naukri)
- ➤ Hired candidates for roles like claims, underwriters, customer support for retail banking and mortgages.
- ➤ Released 70 plus offers individually every month for volume hiring and closed all the positions assigned to me within the given TAT.
- > Handling a team of 4 who directly report to me.
- > Collaboration and Strategy: Collaborating with business leaders for building strong talent pool.
- Recruiting strategy for banking roles for the Leadership level.
- ➤ Partnership with HRBP Business Partner on Internal employee mobility, IJP/Promotions, recruitment strategy and policy guidance.
- ➤ Working on Workday portal in regard to screening of candidates, filtering the right pool of candidates, releasing the offers, BGV verification till the time candidate gets on-boarded.
- ➤ Diversity and Inclusion: Championing and integrating Diversity & Inclusion into hiring strategies. Drive the TA programs to increase women talent in organization.
- ➤ Talent Branding: Drive branding through a variety of channels and go-to-market strategies using social media, Industry events and forums.
- > Responsible in taking care of the rehire candidates as per the Wells Fargo policy.

Report

- Weekly Report To Reporting Manager
- ➤ Generate Monthly Report for the entire month which includes Headcount, Current Openings/Closed Positions/Offered /In progress/Offer Dropped, New Joiners Data, Recruitment Activity (List of Open positions, Total No of Applications Received (Job Portal, Consultant, Walk-in & Status).

HR Executive | Accenture | Team Lease

Aug 2021 – April 2022 Chennai, Tamil Nadu

> Supporting the complete recruitment process from manpower requirement analysis to successful on-boarding

- ➤ Coordinating with Technical Panel for understanding their requirements, defining job positions advertising vacancies/job postings
- > Resourcing resumes through various job portals, networking sites, internal references or head hunting
- > Screening and shortlisting resumes based on desired skills and experience.
- > Evaluating & selecting skilled candidates by conducting written and verbal tests
- Conducting telephone, HR round and personal interviews in coordination with department heads
- > Scheduling role specific and final round of interviews with the concerned stakeholders and candidates
- Discussing offers & conducting salary negotiation with Employees, facilitating Background Verification Check
- > Preparing offer letter, employment contract and job descriptions, completing joining formalities and documentation
- > Facilitating smooth On-boarding and Orientation of all new joiners, appraising them about company's policies, providing overview of the company and package details during introduction
- Working in coordination with VP & AVP, Technical and Business Verticals Head for Non-Technical Recruitment and Project Leads regarding demand requirement and fulfilment
- Assisting in resolution of skill related & reporting issues, pre-offer follow up & post-offer follow up for timely recruitment
- ➤ Coordinating with Cross-Functional and HR Team Members on Recruitment related and other matters.
- ➤ Collating and presenting various HMIS Reports (Work in Progress Report, Head Count Report) to the Management on weekly, monthly and ad-hoc basis as and when required by the Management/ Department Heads
- ➤ Handling employee/ prospective candidate's issues and presenting a positive image of the company.

HR Recruiter | ESK SOFTWARE Feb. 2021 – July 2021.

- > Sourcing the candidate's profile to find the suitable resource to fill the vacancy of all the requirements depending up on the requirement of the clients.
- > Source, screen, and submit candidate's profiles to the clients as assigned.
- ➤ Ability to prioritize the requirements and execute multiple tasks.
- > Talent Connect is to schedule calls and interviews to the candidates who are new into market and informing about the interview timings and the contact person.
- > Perform end-to-end recruitment activity.
- Assist candidates and client HR co coordinator as the initial point of contact by answering calls and emails.
- > Providing immediate resolution or careful redirection to escalated support resources.
- ➤ Manage the complete offer process from getting the expectations of candidate to preparing the offer to getting approvals and releasing the same to the selected

individual.

HR Business Associate – Talent management | COGNIZANT | JAN 2019- MAR 2020

- ➤ Involved in various activities as Talent Management Including Induction, Employee queries Retention activities.
- > Engagement Activities, Awards and Recognitions, Compliances Data management etc.
- ➤ Develop and implement employee engagements activities- Touch Points like One-on-One, Skip levels, Town halls, Rewards & recognition programs, surveys etc.
- > Employee Career Management based on their performances on promotion cycle.
- ➤ Handling Employee Relations & Grievance, Queries, Initiate performance management throughout the BU Unit/ Project.
- > Setting expectation to Entry level trainees on denying the project and location constraints.
- ➤ Handling of Misconduct Policy issues for associates doing violations.

SYSTEM ENGINEER | HCL TECHNOLOGY | APRIL 2016- MAR 2018

· L1 Support Engineer for US client – Club corp.

EDUCATION

MBA: D B Jain – 2105 Madras University - Chennai, Tamil Nadu

B.Com (Corporate secretaryship): Mar 2013 JBAS College.

SKILLS

- > Talent Acquisition
- > Onboarding & Induction
- Background Verification
- Vendor Management
- > Salary Negotiation.
- ➤ Job description & Evaluation
- ➤ Volume hiring / Bulk hiring.
- > Customer support hiring.
- ➤ BFSI hiring.
- > Employee Engagement.
- > Stakeholder Management.
- > Campus hiring.